Alchemy is a science where one understands the structure of matter, breaks it down, then rebuilds it.
錬金術は物質を理解分解再構築する科学なり
However, it is not an all-powerful technique,
as one cannot create something out of nothing.
されど　万能の技にはあらず
無から有を生ずることあたわず
If one wishes to gain something,
one must present something of equal value.
何かを得ようと欲すれば
必ず同等の代価を支払うものなり
This is the concept of equivalent exchange, the fundamental basis of alchemy.
これすなわち錬金術の基本　等価交換なり
However, there is a taboo in alchemy. Human transmutation.
錬金術師に禁忌あり
そは人体錬成なり
One must not commit this act.
これ何人も犯すことなかれ
I've still got a lot of years ahead of me
この想いを　消してしまうには
Kono omoi wo keshiteshimau niwa
To just erase these feelings?
まだ人生長いでしょ？
Mada jinsei nagai desho?
To just erase these feelings?
まだ人生長いでしょ？
I want to go back and finish
やり残してるコト
Yarinokoshiteru koto
The things that I've yet to finish.
やり直してみたいから
Yarinaoshite mitai kara
I was supposed to be chasing after my ongoing dream,
夢のつづき　追いかけていたはずなのに
Yume no tsuzuki oikaketeita hazu nanoni
Yet I faltered over others while walking this thin, winding path.
曲がりくねった　細い道　人につまずく
Magarikunetta hosoi michi hito ni tsumazuku
It's not that I want to return to those days.
あの頃みたいにって　戻りたい訳じゃないの
Ano koro mitainitte modoritai wake ja nai no
I'm searching for the sky I lost.
無くしてきた空を　探してる
Nakushitekita sora wo sagashiteru
Don't make that sad face, as if you've fallen victim.
わかってくれますように
Wakatte kuremasu youni
As if you want people to pity you.
犠牲になったような　悲しい顔はやめてよ
Gisei ni natta youna kanashii kao wa yameteyo
Tears aren't the end of your sins.
罪の最後は涙じゃないよ
Tsumi no saigo wa namida ja nai yo
You have to bear them painfully, forever.
ずっと苦しく背負ってくんだ
Zutto kurushiku seottekunda
Who are you waiting for in the maze of emotions,
出口見えない感情迷路に
Deguchi mienai kanjoumeiro ni
Where you can't even see the exit?
誰を待ってるの？
Dare wo matteruno?
I want to blurt it out more justly,
白いノートに綴ったように
Shiroi nooto ni tsuzutta youni
Just like how I wrote it in my white notebook.
もっと素直に吐き出したいよ
Motto sunao ni hakidashitai yo
What do you want to run from?
何から　逃れたいんだ
Nani kara nogaretainda
That thing called "reality"?
…現実ってやつ？
Genjitsu tte yatsu?
I just want to scream out,
叶えるために　生きてるんだって
Kanaeru tame ni ikiterundatte
"I'm only living to fulfill my wish." Can you hear me?
叫びたくなるよ　聞こえていますか？
Sakebitaku naru yo kikoeteimasuka?
I can't take the safe way out of everything.
無難になんて　やってられないから
Bunan ni nante yatterarenaikara
I don't even have a place to return to.
…帰る場所も無いの
Kaeru basho mo nai no
I'm always thankful for everyone's kindness,
優しさには　いつも感謝してる
Yasashisa ni wa itsumo kansha shiteru
That's why I want to become stronger. (I'm on the way)
だから強くなりたい(I'm on the the
(I'm on the way)
Dakara tsuyoku naritai (I'm on the way)
This is reminding me of the old days.
懐かしくなる
Natsukashiku naru
This pain is all right with me.
こんな痛みも歓迎じゃん
Konna itami mo kangei jan
マルコーの研究資料がある
The First Branch of the National Central Library, where Marcoh's research data was kept, was burned down.
国立中央図書館第一分館は　火災により消失
エドたちは　司書であったシェスカの協力により
Ed and Al obtain the research data with the help of Sheska, a former librarian. However...
研究資料を手に入れる
だが…
The ingredients of philosopher's stones...
賢者の石の材料は
...are live humans.
生きた人間だ
更なる真実を求め
Seeking more of the truth, Ed and Al sneak into the abandoned Research Laboratory 5.
エドとアルは　廃棄された第五研究所に忍び込む
You're pretty fast for a guy so big.
でかい割にはいい動きだな
そうでなくちゃやりがいがねぇ
Else it wouldn't be fun for me!
Who are you?!
だ　誰だ
I'm Number 66.
オレはナンバー６６
That's just my work name, though.
もっとも仕事上の呼び名だがな
I'll dismantle you neatly,
綺麗に解体してやっからよ
so go ahead and wail!
安心して泣き叫べ
What the heck is this?
なんだこりゃ
Could it be what's used to transmute philosopher's stones?
ひょっとして賢者の石を錬成するための
Precisely.
そのとおり
どこの小僧か知らんが
I don't know who you are, but I'm amazed you figured
that out by just looking at the transmutation circle, boy.
錬成陣を見ただけでそれが分かるとはな
なんだ　おっさんは
Who are you, old man?
My duty is to guard this area.
私はここの守護を任されている者
I suppose I'll introduce myself as Number 48.
とりあえずナンバー４８と名乗っておこうか
ちなみに　おっさんではない
And I'm not an old man, either.
ここに入り込んだ部外者は
I've been instructed to eliminate any outsiders who have infiltrated the building.
すべて排除するよう命じられている
Don't think badly of me, boy.
悪く思うな　小僧
Same goes for you...
そっちこそ
Don't take it too badly when you get beaten by a boy.
小僧に倒されても悪く思わないでくれよ
ふん　錬金術師か
An alchemist, huh?
Let's see how good you are.
どれ　手並み拝見
Looks like that arm saved your life!
義手で命拾いしたな
But my beloved sword even slices through steel!
だが　我が愛刀は鋼さえも貫く
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
おいおいおい
Do you not have a body in there?
ひょっとしておっさん　その中空っぽじゃねぇの
I'm amazed you noticed.
よく気がついたな
I spar with someone like you all the time.
あんたみたいなのと
しょっちゅう手合わせしてるんでねぇ
Ah, so there's someone in this state in the outside world, too, eh?
ほう　表の世界にも私と同じのがいるのか
ちっ　イヤになるね
I don't like this at all.
That there's some idiot other than me who'd come up with the idea of affixing a soul to a suit of armor.
オレ以外に魂を鎧に定着させるなんてことを
考えるバカがいるなんてよ
Let me introduce myself again.
改めて名乗ろう
48 was my death row number.
４８は死刑囚ナンバー
When I still had my body, I was called Slicer the Homicide.
生前というべきか
生身の体があったときは
殺人鬼スライサーと呼ばれていた
Death row. Just as I thought.
やっぱ死刑囚か
Hey, this place makes philosopher's stones out of criminals on death row, right?
なあ　ここって死刑囚を材料にして
賢者の石を作ってるんだよな
それには答えかねる
That I cannot answer.
I was simply hired for my skills, given this body,
and stationed here as a watchdog.
私はただ腕を買われて　この体を与えられ
ここの番犬に置かれているだけだ
Which means there's a seal somewhere that mediates the soul and the armor.
ってことは　魂と鎧を仲立ちする印がどこかにある
Precisely.
そう　そのとおり
This seal of blood...
この血印
If you destroy it, you win.
これを壊せば　お前の勝ちだ
You're awfully kind to let me in on your weakness.
弱点を教えてくれるとは親切だな
私は戦いに緊張感を求めるタイプなのでな
I'm the type that seeks thrills in fighting.
Since you're so kind, want to let me off the hook?
親切ついでに見逃してくれない
Was that worth a try?
なんつってみたり
Do you really think a murderer is just going to let his prey get away?
殺人鬼が目の前の獲物を黙って見逃すわけなかろう
Here I come!
いざ　参る
Like~I~said~
だから
Elicia's having her third birthday!
エリシアが３歳になるんだよ
Lt. Colonel Hughes, I'm working right now.
East City
Eastern Headquarters
ヒューズ中佐　私は今仕事中なのだ
What a coincidence! So am I.
奇遇だなぁ　オレも仕事中だ
But seriously, she's so cute.
いや　もうかわいいのなんの
I get it! Quit calling me about your daughter all the time.
分かったから　いちいち娘自慢の電話を掛けてくるな
And with an army line, too!
それも軍の回線で
Not just my daughter.
娘だけじゃないぞ
I'm proud of my wife, too!
妻も自慢だ
All right, all right, I'll listen to your story, too.
分かった分かった　オレも聞いてやるよ
About your cute and charming "Scar" you're so proud of.
お前の自慢のかわいい かわいい
スカーのことを
We've found several unidentified bodies.
身元不明の遺体が多数見つかっている
They're pretty decomposed, so it's
difficult to determine if he's in there.
いずれも腐敗が進んでいて　確認が難しい
There haven't been any sightings of him in the East,
so as of now, most people believe he's dead.
東部近隣での目撃情報もないから
死んだとする意見が多いのが　現状だ
If that's the case, we can probably set
the Elric brothers free of their escorts soon.
その様子なら
エルリック兄弟の護衛もじきに解けそうだな
Is Major Armstrong still in charge of that?
護衛は　今もアームストロング少佐が
Nah, apparently the Major's subordinates have taken over.
いや　少佐の部下が引き継いでるらしい
They got us!
やられた
I knew they were being too quiet...
やけに静かだと思ったら
ああ　職務怠慢で
Major Armstrong's going to kill us for dereliction of duty!
アームストロング少佐に絞り上げられるぅ
Those brats! They should put themselves in their escorts' shoes every once in a while!
あのガキども
護衛の身にもなれってのよ
行くわよ
Let's go!
Huh? Where?
えっ　どこへ
Where do you think?
決まってるでしょ
The former Research Laboratory 5!
元第五研究所よ
なんだ　肩に違和感が
Huh? Something doesn't feel right in my shoulder...
...this time so it would be more resistant to rust,
but that makes it less durable, so don't overuse...
今回の機械鎧はさびにくくした代わりに
強度が下がったから
あんまりムチャは
If I don't settle this quick...
こりゃ早くケリつけないと
...I'm in trouble!
やばいな
You're almost like a monkey.
まるで猿だな
What'd you say?!
なんだと　こら
I haven't had worthy prey like you in a while. I'm delighted.
久しぶりに手応えのある獲物でうれしいぞ
だが　その傷と疲労では勝負は見えている
But with your wounds and fatigue, the outcome is clear.
My companion should have disposed of your companion by now.
お前の仲間は今ごろ私の連れが始末しているはずだ
Is your companion strong?
その連れって強いのか
He is. Weaker than me, though.
強いぞ　私よりは弱いがな
No worries there, then.
だったら心配いらねぇや
I've been in a lot of fights with him
since we were little, and I've never won.
オレ　昔っからあいつとケンカして
勝ったことないんだ
Dammit, stay still and let me cut you, hippo!
くっそ　ちっとはおとなしく斬られやがれってんだ
このデカ物
That body...
あっ　その体
I've got a few circumstances of my own.
ちょっと訳ありでなぁ
Actually, let me tell you a story.
そうだ　昔話をしてやろう
You've heard of him, too, haven't you?
おめぇも聞いたことあるだろう
A middle-aged man by the name of Barry.
バリーって名前のおやじの話だ
A long, long time ago, there was a middle-aged man here in Central named Barry who loved to cook.
昔々ここセントラルに
バリーという料理好きのおやじがいました
Barry loved to cut up meat.
バリーは肉を切り分けるのが大好きでした
But one day, it got to the point he couldn't satisfy himself with just beef and pork,
でもある日
牛や豚だけでは我慢できなくなったバリーは
夜な夜な街に出ては
so he started to go out into the city during nighttime to cut up humans.
人間を解体するようになったのでした
Barry was eventually caught, but the number of people who fell victim to him was twenty-three.
やがてバリーは捕まりましたが
それまでに餌食になった人間は２０と３人
After terrorizing the hell out of the residents of Central, he was sentenced to death by hanging.
セントラル市民を恐怖のどん底にたたき込んだその男は
当然絞首刑になりました
And everyone lived happily ever after...
めでたし　めでたし
ってのが世の中に出回ってる昔話だ
...is the story given to the public.
But there's actually a sequel to the story.
ところがこいつには続きがあってよ
Barry isn't actually dead.
バリーは実は死んじゃいない
He's alive and has been assigned to watch over a certain somewhere.
とある場所の番人を任され生きている
Though he's had his body taken away.
ただし肉体を取り上げられてな
That's right! The man standing in front of you right now is the infamous serial killer, Barry the Chopper!
そう
今てめぇの目の前にいるオレこそかの有名な殺人鬼
バリー·ザ·チョッパーその人だ
Sorry, I've never heard of you.
ごめん　聞いたことない
I was born in the countryside in the East, so...
僕　東部の田舎の生まれだから
Yeah, but even if you've never heard the story, shouldn't you give some kind of reaction?!
知らないにしたって
この体見りゃそれなりのリアクションあんだろ
Something like...
もっとこう　「ぎゃあ」とか　「なんだ その体」とか
"AHHHH!", or "What's with that body?!"
AHHHH! W-W-W-What's with that body?!
ぎゃあ　ななななんだその体
That hurt, you know.
傷つくなぁ
Oh, so you were sentenced to death, too.
あっ　そうか　死刑仲間か
ビビらせやがって
Scaring me like that...
僕は犯罪者じゃない
I'm not a criminal!
Huh? Then why?
じゃあなんでだ
Well... I've had a few circumstances of my own.
ちょっと訳ありでね
My older brother affixed my soul when I lost my body.
体がなくなったとき
兄さんが魂を錬成してくれたんだ
Brother?
兄貴　げへへへっそうか兄貴が
I see. Your brother, eh?
What's so funny?
何がおかしいんだよ
Are you guys really brothers?
その兄貴とおめぇほんとに兄弟なのか
I mean, our personalities are different, but...
そりゃ性格は違うけどさ
Oh. No, no, no, that's not what I meant.
あっいやいやいや　そういう意味じゃなくて
What I meant to say was, maybe you're
an armor doll your "brother" created?
おめぇよ
その兄貴とやらにつくられた鎧人形じゃねぇのか
Huh?
Does your real human self really exist?
元の人間なんてほんとにいるのかよ
Of course it does!
いるに決まってるだろ
僕は間違いなく
I'm Alphonse Elric, a human! No doubt about it!
アルフォンス·エルリックという人間だ
How can you be so sure?
どうしてそう思えるんだ
Because I have memories from when I was born!
だって　生まれてからの記憶はちゃんとあるもの
What if those were created, too?
それもつくりもんだったらどうすんだよ
But Winry and Granny...
ウィンリィや　ばっちゃんだって
They're probably in on it, too.
そりゃああれだ　グルだな
なあ　そうなんだよ
Yeah, that's how it is.
おめぇなんて最初からいなかったのさ
You didn't exist to begin with.
T-Then... what about you?
じゃ　じゃあ　あんたはどうなんだよ
It's simple.
簡単なことだ
Don't move! This place is restric-
動くな　ここは立ち入り
See?
ほらな
オレは生きた人間をぶった斬るのが大好きなんだ
I love hacking live humans!
I love to kill, and I can't get enough of it!
殺しが好きで好きでたまんねぇんだよ
I exist to kill.
我殺す故に我あり
That's the only proof I need to know that I am who I am!
オレがオレである証しなんざそれだけで十分さ
ほう　弟はそんなに強いのか
So your little brother is that strong, eh?
Then I had better defeat you quickly.
ならば早々に貴様を倒さねばならんな
Al, now!
アル　今だ
何っ
What?!
How foul!
卑怯な
Like there are rules in a fight!
ケンカに卑怯もクソもあるか
What's wrong? My blood seal isn't broken yet.
どうした　まだ私の血印は壊されていないぞ
Just hurry up and dest-
さっさと破壊し
There's something I want to ask you.
あんたに聞きたいことがある
About the philosopher's stone?
賢者の石か
Spill everything you know.
知ってること全部吐いてもらおうか
No can do.
言えんな
Hey now, the loser shouldn't be putting on a brave front.
おいおい　負け犬が粋がるんじゃねぇよ
I... haven't lost yet.
まだ　負けてなどおらん
バ バカな
Impossible!
言い忘れたが
I forgot to mention it. Slicer the Homicide...
スライサーという殺人鬼は
兄弟二人組だったってわけよ
...Was actually a duo of brothers.
The head and body are two different people?!
頭と胴体で 別個かよ
反則くせぇ
That's cheating.
ケンカに卑怯もクソもあるかと言ったのは誰だったかな
And who's the one who said there aren't any rules in a fight?
Let's go for Round 2, runt.
さあ 第２ラウンドといこうぜ
おチビさん
チビ言うな
Don't call me a runt!
おおっと　錬成する暇は与えねぇぜ
Whoa, I'm not going to give you time for a transmutation!
くっそ　血ぃ出しすぎだ
Shit, I lost too much blood.
クラクラしてきやがった
I'm starting to feel dizzy...
This is bad...
やべぇ
Bad...
I'm...
死ぬ　死ぬ　死ぬ
I'm going to die!
とどめだ
This is it for you!
痛ぇ
Ouch...
イヤなヤツのこと思い出させやがって
Making me remember that jerk.
あいつと同じことしちまったじゃねぇか
I just did the same thing he did.
You've gone and done it now, brat!
やりやがったなこのガキ
うわっ　気色悪っ
Man, that's disgusting!
Brother!
兄者
情けないが我らの負けだ
It's shameful, but we lost.
You're not going to say something like, "Hey, we're actually a trio", are ya?
実は三人兄弟でしたとか言わない
言わん言わん
We won't, we won't.
小僧　さっさと我らを破壊するがいい
Just destroy us already, boy.
人殺しは勘弁しろ
Spare me from having to murder someone.
こんな体の我らが人か
You consider us human?
あんたらのことを人じゃないと認めちまったら
If I didn't accept you two as human,
it would mean I'm doing the same to my brother, too.
オレはオレの弟を人じゃないと認めることになる
おらおらどうした鎧人形
Hey now, what's wrong, armor doll?!
僕は鎧人形じゃない
I'm not an armor doll!
そう思ってるだけさ
That's what you think.
Did you really exist to begin with?
本物のお前なんていたのか
ほんとにいたのかよ
Are you sure about that?
自分が鎧人形じゃねぇって証明する方法があるぜ
There's a way to prove you're not an armor doll.
お前にも血印があんだろ
You've got a blood seal, too, don't you?
そいつを自分で消すんだよ
Erase it yourself.
それで死ねばお前は本物だ
If you die, you were human!
それでも動いてりゃ鎧人形さ
If you're still movin', then you're an armor doll!
でっ できるわけないだろそんなこと
I-I can't do something like that!
ちっ　だったらオレが　やってやるぜ
Then I'll do it for you!
My little brother is human.
オレの弟は人間だ
So are you two.
あんたらも人間だ
だから　殺しはイヤだ
That's why I don't want to kill you.
Brother?
兄者
我ら兄弟　物心ついたときから盗み壊し殺してきた
Us two have been stealing, destroying,
and murdering ever since we came of age.
それがこんな姿となって初めて人間扱いされるとは
And we're being treated as humans for the first time, after being turned into this?
おもしろい
Interesting.
I'll tell you everything as a parting gift, boy.
小僧　置き土産だ
すべて教えてやる
賢者の石を作り
The one who created the philosopher's stone and told us to guard this place is...
我らにここを守るように命じた者は
That was close.
危ない危ない
You can't be talking about things like that, 48.
ダメよ４８
余計なことしゃべっちゃ
あらら　なんで鋼のおチビさんがいるのさ
Huh? What's the Fullmetal runt doing here?
困った子ねぇ
What a troublesome child.
どうやってここのことを知ったの
How did you find out about this place?
兄者　兄者　兄者
Brother! Brother?!
BROTHER!!!
やかましいんだよ　このボケが
You're so annoying, dumbass!
おめぇら　貴重な人柱を殺しちまうところだったんだぞ
You guys were about to kill a precious sacrifice!
分かってんのか
Don't you understand?!
計画に差し支えたら　どう責任取るつもりだ
What were you gonna do if you screwed up the plan?!
Huh?!
なんだ貴様ら
Who the hell are you two?!
計画ってなんだ　人柱ってどういうことだ
What plan?!
What do you mean by sacrifice?!
Oh? This runt is ready to go.
あら　やる気満々だよ　このおチビさん
チビチビうるせぇんだよ
Quit calling me a runt!
A runt's a runt, don't you agree?
チビはチビだろ　おチビさん
やだなぁ　ケンカは
I don't like fighting.
ケガしたら痛いじゃない
It hurts if you get injured.
てめぇが売ったケンカだろうが　買ってやるから
You're the one that started it!
I'll beat you to a...
故障みたいね
Looks like it's broken.
WHAT?!
ラッキー
Lucky me!
腕が壊れてよかったね
Good thing your arm broke.
余計なケガしなくて済んだんだからさ
You didn't have to suffer any other injuries.
いいこと　坊や
Listen, boy.
あなたは生かされてるってことを忘れるんじゃないわよ
Don't forget you're being kept alive.
またこんな坊やが現れると困るわ
It'll be troublesome if a boy like this
happens to find this place again.
ここ焼いてしまいましょ
Let's burn it down.
オレさ　ずっとお前に言おうと思ってたけど
Hey... there's something I've always wanted to ask you...
怖くて言えなかったことがあるんだ
...but I've been too scared to.
兄さんは何を言おうとしてた
What was Brother trying to say?
怖くて言えなかったことって
"Something he was too scared to say?"
怖くて言えなかったこと
Something he was too scared to...
...maybe you're an armor doll your "brother" created?
兄貴とやらにつくられた鎧人形じゃねぇのか
元の人間なんてほんとにいるのかよ
Does your real human self really exist?
What's wrong, armor dollie?
どうしたどうした鎧人形ちゃん
うるさい　僕は
Shut up!! I'm...
認めちまえよ　楽になるぜ
Just accept it. It'll make you feel better.
隙だらけだぜ　デカ物
You're full of openings, hippo!
あれっ
Huh?!
動かないで
Don't move!
おとなしく投降しなさい
Just surrender.
面倒なことになっちまったな
This isn't good...
軍曹　退避
Sergeant... evacuate!
何してるの　早く逃げるのよ
What are you doing?!
Hurry and get out of here!
But Brother's still inside!
でも　まだ中に兄さんが
なんですって
What did you say?!
Well, this leaves me no choice.
うん　こりゃあれだな
I guess I'll just get out of here!
素直にとんずら
あっ　こら
Hey!
You guys better run, too!
おめぇらも早く逃げろよ
待て
Wait!
Brother! Brother!
兄さん　兄さん
退避して　あなたまで巻き込まれてしまう
Get out of here!
You'll get caught in it, too!
でも
But!
Howdy.
ちわっす
荷物お届けに上がりました
A package for you.
兄さん
Brother?!
命に別状はないけど
He isn't in danger or anything, but he lost a lot of blood, so get him to a hospital quick, okay?
出血がひどいから早く病院に入れてやってねぇ
あとさ　あんまりムチャしないように
Oh yeah, and make sure you guys keep an eye on him so he doesn't do anything too reckless.
あんたたちしっかり見張っててよね
貴重な人材なんだからさ
He's an important guy, after all.
And who are you?
あなたは
ロス少尉　早く
Second Lt. Ross, hurry!
軍曹　手を貸して
Sergeant, lend me a hand!
血まみれじゃないですか
He's covered in blood!
話は後
We'll talk later! You'd better get out of here, too-
あなたも早く逃げ
あれ　いない
Huh? He's gone.
出せよ
Let us out!
オレたちを殺す気か
You plannin' on lettin' us die?!
ええい　うるさい　落ち着け
Shut up! Pipe down!
What a nice sound.
いい音だ
これは爆発物で建物が崩れ落ちる音ですよ
This is the sound of a building crumbling due to explosives.
この近さだと
Judging from the proximity... it's probably Research Laboratory 5 next door.
隣の第五研究所ですかね
ああ　いい音だ
Ah, what a nice sound...
体の底に響く実にいい音だ
It shakes me to my bones.
私語は慎めキンブリー
Shut your trap, Kimbley!
Ah, I apologize.
やあ　失敬
イシュヴァールのせん滅戦を思い出して
It reminded me of the Ishbal Extermination, and it just made me so happy...
ついうれしくなりましてね
兄貴とやらにつくられた鎧人形じゃねぇのか
...maybe you're an armor doll your "brother" created?
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
あの日見た空　茜色の空を
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
Do you remember it from that day?
ねえ　君は覚えていますか
Nee kimi wa oboeteimasuka
We made a promise and a vow while the early summer wind circled us.
約束　契り　初夏の風が包む
Yakusoku chigiri shoka no kaze ga tsutsumu
And we clung close together.
二人　寄り添った
Futari yorisotta
Your forced smile
無理な笑顔の裏
Muri na egao no ura
Holds elongated shadows.
伸びた影をかくまう
Nobita kage wo kakumau
I pretend not to notice and continue on.
だから　気づかぬふり　再生を選ぶ
Dakara kizukanu furi saisei wo erabu
All the while waiting for you to deliver some news at the table.
テーブルの上の　震えない知らせ　待ち続けて
Teeburu no ue no furuenai shirase machitsuzukete
Empty nights, mornings that will never arrive,
空白の夜も　来るはずのない朝も
Kuuhaku no yoru mo kuru hazu no nai asa mo
I could see them from a mile away.
全部わかってたんだ
Zenbu wakattetanda
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
あの日見た空　茜色の空を
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
I'm sure you'll remember it one day.
ねえ　 いつか思い出すでしょう
Nee itsuka omoidasu deshou
While holding the promise we couldn't keep,
果たせなかった　約束を抱いて
Hatasenakatta yakusoku wo idaite
We take our first steps down our own paths.
二人　歩き出す
Futari arukidasu
で　セントラルだがな
And so, about Central...
国家錬金術師を統制する上層部が
The bigwigs who oversee State Alchemists are going through a labor shortage thanks to Scar.
スカーのお陰で人手不足になっている
ほう
Oh?
マスタング大佐のセントラル招聘も近いって噂だぜ
Rumor is it won't be long before
Colonel Mustang is invited to Central.
セントラルか　悪くないな
Central, huh?
Not bad.
気をつけろよ
You'd better watch out.
その若さで上層部に食い込むとなると敵も増えるぞ
If you manage to get to the top at that age,
you'll gain a lot of enemies.
もとより覚悟のうえだ
I'm prepared for it.
セントラルの先輩としての忠告だ
Words of wisdom from your senior in Central.
お前さんを理解して支えてくれる人間を
Have a lot of people who understand and are willing to support you.
一人でも多くつくっておけ
だから
So...
早く嫁さんもらえ
Hurry up and get married.
やかましいわ
None of your business!
なんでぇ　いきなり切りやがって
Why'd he hang up on me like that?
ヒューズ中佐　私用電話は程々にしてくださいね
Lt. Colonel Hughes, please keep personal calls to a minimum!
あっ　ごめん
Oh, sorry.
日本語字幕仕上げ：FAYFAY
エドワード·エルリックは言葉を躊躇い
Edward Elric hesitates to speak his words...
アルフォンス·エルリックは言葉によって惑わされる
...and Alphonse Elric becomes perplexed by Barry's words.
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
そしてただ一つ　確かなもの
The one certainty is that a girl's memories hold the truth.
少女の記憶が真実を告げる
次回　鋼の錬金術師　FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
第九話　創られた想い
Episode 9, Created Feelings.
心が揺れる　それは信じていたから
Their hearts waver because they put their trust in each other.